Svyatoslav Kurka

Front-End Developer

Solution-driven Front-End Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 3+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.



Contact

Work History

Address

Newark, NJ 07106

Phone

8622551395

E-mail

svlawd@gmail.com

WWW

https://rb.gy/im85

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/svyatoslavkurka



Technical Profile

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML/CSS (SCSS/SASS)
- React.js
- Redux/Redux-Toolkit
- Next.is
- RESTful API
- MaterialUI/TailwindUI /ChakraUI/Bootstrap 5
- Git
- NPM/Yarn
- Docker
- MongoDB/PocketBase

2021-09 -Current

2021-11

Front End Developer

DEV SIT, Kyiv

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.
- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in deadline-driven environment.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code.

2020-12 - Front End Developer

CB, Lviv

- Improved and expanded project platforms using latest web technologies to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.
- Designed reusable and reliable code for use

- Firebase
- Figma



Ukrainian - Fluent

English - Advanced

within distributed cloud environments.

- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.

Front-end ReactJS Developer 2020-10

Autoparts | Start-up, Lviv

- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.
- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs, and improving functionality.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.

2020-01 - ReactJS Engineer 2020-03

Astomi, Lviv

- Assembled and addressed technical and design requirements, integrating user-facing and front-end elements to maintain web presence effectiveness.
- Worked with marketing team to deliver digital creative campaigns and initiatives.
- Use regulatory and compliance standards for user interface designs.
- Delivered responsive web design projects in Agile framework.
- Supported A/B testing concepts and version control.
- Followed SDLC best practices within Agile environment to produce rapid iterations for clients.
- Integrated enhancements into web design to

improve user stickiness, smooth functionality, and boost load times.

• Identified bottlenecks and bugs and devised solutions.



Certifications

2022-12 SoftServe React Marathon



Education

2009-09 -**High School Diploma** 2020-05

Humanitarian Gymnasium Named After Olena Stepaniv - Lviv